### **NAGASHREE S**

# (Operations / Project Manager) Military Veteran

□: nagashrees99@gmail.com +91 - 9060835473 https://www.linkedin.com/in/nagashree-s-245456163/

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

A dynamic professional with 5+ years of military and 4+years of corporate experience in the domain of Project and Operations Management, Human Resource, and Administration Management. An adaptable leader with a "Will do "attitude who has a drive for problem-solving and achieving organizational objectives through strategic Leadership, people, and resource management, and effective communication.

### **KEY SKILLS**

HR Management Client Relations Employee Relations IT Infrastructure

Training and Mentoring Data Analysis Risk Planning

#### **DATA TOOLS**

Microsoft PowerPoint Microsoft Office Amazon DALI ITIL foundation (Infosys)

OS Solaris/Win/Linux Microsoft Word

## **EDUCATION**

- BSC (EMCs) from University of Mysore -- 71.47% (Jun 2005-May 2008)

- PGDCA from Centre for Development of Applied Computers (C-DAC) -- A+ grade (Aug 2006-Jul 2007)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **AMAZON**

### HR (ERC DLS) Associate

(Sep 2021 – Oct 2021)

- Provided HR Assistance to the Amazon employees in India and USA with accurate, consistent, and timely responses to queries
- Responsible for managing Leave of Absence and Accommodation needs for employees
- Hands-on experience on Internal Tool -DALI
- Basic knowledge of US legislation Leave of Absence and Accommodations
- Basic knowledge of US Federal and state leave and Disability

## **CONSULTING SPECIALIST (FREELANCE)**

( Mar 2017- Jan 2019)

- Provided Support and Plans for MAK ltd to streamline selling strategies, Cost cutting, and offer operators assistance for the supply of strategic assets to the Indian Navy
- Liaise between Airport Specialist Vehicle Department (Indian Navy) and MAK Controls & Systems Ltd for contract negotiation and finalizing the agreements
- Utilize Operators Cost data to produce sales reports & Profit and loss statements thereby undertaking financial analysis and forecast

### INDIAN NAVY

### Project Manager (Mar 2014- Feb 2017)

- Managed a team of 75 members to undertake all Avionics-related maintenance, at a fully operational air base operating a range of technologically sophisticated aircraft.
- Managed a team of more than 250 Tech and non-Tech crew to ensure 100% serviceability of Aviation related facilities
- Reviewed and implemented a new hiring process which resulted in the retention of 30% of Officers and Sailors, cut the lead time for recurring Civilian employees buy, 22%, and improved training participation by 35%
- Reviewed Contracts and negotiated with Vendors during various Defense procurement of strategic assets and vehicles with top firms such as Boeing, Kirloskar, MAK, and Toyota worth more than Rs 50 crores
- Led a team of more than 50 personnel to help achieve various strategic and Operations missions ensuring consistent implementations of policies, procedures, and operating standards within laid down laws and regulations of the Govt.
- Reviewed and controlled various programs such as retirement benefits, death and disability payouts, widow employment, etc.
- Implemented a new hiring method for Civilian Staff by incorporating training initiatives, while resolving problems and processing related documents

Executive Officer (Dec 2012- Feb 2014)

- Undertook IT projects related to installation and testing of mission-critical components such as radars, weapons, Communication, and other Mission systems to support Aircraft operations
- Budgeting, Vendor negotiation, and purchasing of various Infosec projects as per Ministry of Defense directives by balancing effective resources distribution and managing the lifecycle from initiation to deployment into implementation

- Ensured maintenance of reasonable balance in resource allocations combined with controlling tasks assigned to them to emphasize timeliness and quality of deliverables
- As a part of the IT Security team, built a system worth INR 02 Crores (USD .3 Million) to maintain integrity, confidentiality, and secured Communication using VFH from Aircraft to Ground
- Oversaw Installation of a large-scale data center to support critical ERP solution for Naval Aviation for 2000+ Navy-wide users 24X7
- Developed, implemented, and monitored of a robust Disaster Recovery system that provides Real Time Disaster Recovery sites located at 3 geographically dispersed Commands of the Indian Navy.
- Assessment and purchase of IT Hardware worth more than INR 75 Lakhs for the organization with a strength of over
  250 people which was required for smooth functioning of the Department
- Undertook Risk Assessment & Integrated risk management activities, optimized control, and supported expanding compliance requirements by strict complaints to Govt protocols
- Ensured over 99% incident-free availability of servers and IT systems for close to 2 years.
- Responsible for annual IT Audits and budget of over INR 1 crores (USD 170 K)

#### **INFOSYS TECHNOLOGIES LTD**

**Systems Engineer** 

(Nov 2010 - Nov 2012)

- Maintenance of RDW infrastructure support (Reporting Data Warehouse) systems for client Suncorp thereby providing resolutions for immediate fix and recommended long-term solutions to resolve the root cause
- Worked as a single point of contact between the client and the company's management. Also successfully completed 143 server migration on Solaris platform

**Assistant Engineer** 

(Dec 2009 – Nov 2010)

- Configuration, Maintenance, and setup of the relevant server and system alerts of Sun Solaris 9,10 OS systems
- Performed root cause analysis and Problem Management of various technical bugs and defects
- Provided support which includes the development of minor/major enhancements, and defect fixes, and provided workaround to various Sub-Projects
- Performed various User Audits on servers

**Operations Executive** 

(Feb 2009 - Dec 2009)

- Engaged consultatively with the client and undertook prompt resolution of various issues/tickets within the SLA period
- Engaged with senior-level management executives and rendered system performance stats and weekly reports

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Awarded "Certificate of Excellence" for representing Infosys during various philanthropic activities (CSR) thereby creating a positive social impact
- Represented Infosys at various corporate level Basket Ball tournaments
- Received Appreciation from Commander-in-Chief, Indian Navy for displaying exemplary leadership and Men & Material Management Skills during the Crisis & Disaster relief Ops (2015 Chennai Floods)